You watched the detailed video of the ICICI Lord Elevate health insurance plan last week
and saw how
flexible it is, meaning it can be
considered a very good plan. However, we should also compare the Elevate plan with plans that have
already established goodwill,
meaning they are currently very popular in the health insurance market.
Therefore,
in today's video, we
will compare the ICICI Lord Elevate plan.
Although there are many other good plans,
comparing five or six plans in a single video can cause a lot of
confusion and congestion. To
properly compare health insurance plans
and keep the video length ideal, we will
compare only three plans.
We
can easily do it in a comfortable video length, and this will make it
easier for you to understand. So, friends, in today's
video, we will understand the difference between the ICICI Lord Elevate plan,
Optima Secure, and Ratio 2.0 plans.
What are the differences in their coverage and benefits,
what are the advertising companies offering?
How can you rank these plans based on their coverage and
benefits? We will also learn about the
shortcomings of these plans. That is, only
when we compare them will we know which
plan offers better coverage. At the
end of the video, I will
also give you a price comparison of these three plans
so that
after comparing the features and benefits, you can also check
which plan is the most affordable for you, that
is, you will get it at the lowest premium.
If you are associated with any of the ICICI Lord
Elevate Plan, ADAC Ergo Optima
Secure, and Niva Bhupar Ratio 2.2 plans,
want to take any plan, or already
have these policies, then today's video will
bring complete clarity in your mind, that
is, there will be no confusion.
A comparison video regarding the features and coverages of these three plans will clear all
your confusion.
Without delay, let's quickly
start the video. First of all, friends, we will understand the
eligibility conditions of all these three plans.
After that, we will understand the coverage benefits.
After that, I will explain
what advances you get in each plan. After that,
I will also give my verdict,
what I find lacking in each plan and
what are the good things in each plan.
After that, we will compare the premiums of all these three plans
and also
know that even after paying this premium,
what coverage will you get in which plan, that is,
this is going to be a very comprehensive
detailed video of the comparison of these plans. So, first of all, let's
compare the eligibility conditions. The
first point in the eligibility to buy health insurance plans is the
entry age, that is, what will be the minimum and maximum
entry age for adults and
dependent children. So, first of all, let's
talk about the IIC Lombard Elevate plan.
Here, the entry age for adults is from
18 years to a maximum of 125 years.
That is, you can also say that
because the higher side of age is quite
rare, you can also say that maximum no capping.
And if we talk about dependent
children, then
under the Elevate plan, dependent children can
become a part of this policy from 91 days to 30 years. Now let's talk about
HDFC ARG Optima Secure plan,
here the entry age for adults will be
between 18 to 65 years and
dependent children
can stay in this policy from 91 days to 25 years. Whereas
in the Neva Par Ratio 2.0 plan, the
entry age for adults is the same as Optima
Secure i.e. 18 to
65 years and the age of dependent children
matches that of Elevate, that is,
dependent children can
stay in this policy with their parents from 91 days to 30 years.
If friends, talk about renewal
i.e. you have purchased the policy and taken the policy
in whichever age bracket is mentioned.
After that,
when can you get it renewed? So,
you will be able to get lifelong renewal done in all three plans.  There is
no capping age above. Which plan type
can you take, i.e.
individual or family floater plan? Will
you get options in all these three plans?
Absolutely. In Elevate Plan, Optima
Secure Plan and Ratio 2.2,
you can take individual sum
insured and family floater plan.
Now friends, it is the turn to
understand the sum insured, that is, when you are
buying the policy, how much coverage will you
get in these three plans,
what is the minimum and maximum limit in it. First of all, let us
see the sum insured option of IIC Lombard Elevate Plan.
You can choose from ₹ lakh to ₹ crore
and one more special thing is that here you
also get the option of unlimited sum insured, that is, there is
no limit on your treatment, that is, there is no limit on coverage.
You can also take unlimited sum insured.
Whereas, if we talk about Optima Secure
Plan, here you can get coverage from ₹ lakh  You will
get coverage up to ₹1 crore and under the Reo 2.0
plan, you can choose a sum insured from ₹5 lakh to ₹1 crore as per
your need.
Now friends, when it comes to
tenure, that is, how long a policy
you can buy at one time, then all three plans have
a two and three year option.
If you take a long term policy, then
you will also get a long term discount on the purchase of two and three year policies. All
three plans have
one or more variants in these plans. There are
no variants in the Elevate plan. There is a standard plan, you
can modify it as per your need by
taking different add-ons. There is only
one variant in the Optima Secure plan,
however, if you take a 3-year policy,
then your policy becomes Optima Super Secure, that is,
you will get three times the coverage in it.
We will understand how to get it later in the video. There
are five variants in the Reo 2.0 plan, through which the maximum capping of your sum insured
is decided.
Which variants are there here: Titanium
Plus, Platinum Plus
Apart from Bronze Plus, the company has also launched Gold and Bronze variants.
The difference in these five variants is up to
which limit can you avail their Booster Plus benefit.
So the first point here is the
room rent limit. During treatment,
which category of room can the policy holder take
for treatment? If we talk about
IIC Lombard Elevate plan, then here
under the standard policy you will get a
single private AC room, however, you
can modify this limit through ads. If we
talk about hdfcergo.com,
discharge is done to them. All three
plans cover day treatments, domiciliary
hospitalization or home care
treatment. Domiciliary hospitalization means
treatment at home due to some compulsion,
either the patient is not in a condition to
go to the hospital or beds are not available in the hospitals, then
you will get this coverage in all the three plans. What is home care
treatment?
You are getting treatment at home from a home care service provider on your own will,
which treatment would not be available
in the hospital.  If you want to have it, you can avail that too,
but you will not get the facility of home care treatment under the Elevate plan.
You can also avail home care treatment under Optima Secure and RISH 2.0.
Now friends, it is the turn to
compare the number of days of pre and post hospitalization expenses.
This is the coverage which will
cover the expenses incurred a few days before the treatment and will
cover the doctor's expenses incurred during recovery after discharge.
For how many days do you
get this coverage in all these three plans?
If we talk about ICICI Lombard Elevate plan, then
here the expenses of 90 days pre hospitalization and
180 days post hospitalization will be
covered, whereas in HDFC ARG
Optima Secure plan, 60 days
pre hospitalization and 180 days post hospitalization and
in RISH 2.0 plan
also, the expenses of 60 days pre hospitalization and 180 days
post hospitalization will be covered,
that is, what was the comparison of pre and
post hospitalization expenses
You get more coverage for 30 days in hospitalization. The
post-hospital coverage of
road ambulance is the same in the ICICI Lombard Elevate plan. If a
road ambulance is used during an emergency or normal treatment
and the insurance
company approves your claim, then you get
road ambulance coverage in all three plans. The
next point is
consumer bills coverage, that is, are non-medical
items covered under these policies?
In some plans, this is standard
coverage, and in some, you will have to take an add-on.
First, let's look at the ICICI Lombard Elevate
plan. Here, you will have to cover
consumer bills items through the Claim Protector add-on, which
means
this coverage is not available in the standard policy. However,
you can definitely add it through an add-on.
If we talk about the ADFC ARG Optima
Secure plan,
your consumer bills items are covered through the Protect benefit. This is
absolutely part of the standard policy,
which means you do not need to take any extra add-on.
And if we talk about the Ratio 2.0
plan,  So, there too, you will have to take the Safeguard and
Safeguard Plus add-ons. If you
want to add non-medical items to your policy coverage, then now
comes the very important coverage related to maternity,
vaccination, and newborn baby coverage. Will
these three plans
provide this coverage? If we talk about the ICCA
Lord Elevate plan, then here you also
get coverage for maternity, newborn baby cover, and vaccination, but
you will have to take it as an add-on, that is, if you
add these coverages to your policy, then
you will have to pay extra money. Whereas,
you will not get any maternity-related coverage under the Optima Secure and Ratio 2.0 plans. However,
if you take the Aspire plan of Niva Upa instead of Ratio 2.0, then
you
can cover maternity under the Miracle Benefit. But here we are
talking about Ratio 2.0, so
you will not get coverage for it here. Let's
talk about modern treatments, which is very
important coverage considering today's times.
Here, ICICI Lombard
In the Elevate plan, all the
12 listed modern treatments under the standard plan are
covered up to some limits by IRDA. There is no
capping or sub-limit on any modern treatment.
If we talk about STFC or Optima Secure, then there is
no mention of any coverage related to modern treatment in its policy document, prospectus or brochure. That is, it is not written anywhere
that the company will provide this coverage. Although it is
possible that the insurance
company may say telephonically that this coverage is included,
but whatever is included or
excluded must be written
in the policy wording document of every health insurance policy.
Therefore, I do not consider modern
treatments to be covered under the Optima Secure plan.
Although it is
possible that these modern treatments may be covered,
but if I look at the
policy wording document issued by the insurance company, then
they are not covered. Now comes the turn of the Ratio
2.0 plan. Modern
treatments are covered under this plan.  There is
no supplement
except for some robotic surgeries which have a
sub-limit of ₹1 lakh. All other modern
treatments are covered up to the sum insured.
Surrogacy and Usai Donor Cover: Both these
coverages are related to child birth and
maternity, that is, if a
policy holder wants a surrogate mother or
someone other than the biological mother to give
birth to their baby, or if
they want coverage of that Usai donor, then
coverage of up to ₹1 lakh can be available for such treatment under the IIC Lombard Elevate Plan. Coverage of up to ₹1 lakh can be available
for both the surrogate mother and the Usai donor. However,
this coverage is not available under the Optima Secure Plan and Ratio 2.0 Plan. Let's talk about the cumulate bonus,
friends, that is, if you do
not make any claim on the policy for the entire year
or even if you make a claim,
how much cumulate bonus
or no claim bonus will you get on successful renewal. Talking about the Elevate Plan,
Here you get a guaranteed no
claim bonus of 20%, which means if
you have not made any claim in the entire year
and get your policy renewed,
then your sum insured will increase by 20
%. It can increase up to a maximum of 100%. Now
why is it called Guaranteed No Claim Bonus here?
Because this cumulative bonus will
not expire on any claim unless you
use the money of this cumulative bonus for treatment.
If we talk about Optima Secure plan, then
here you get Plus Benefit
irrespective of claim, which means whether you make a claim or
not, your sum assured will increase by 50% every year
and the maximum can be 100%, that is, double your sum
insured. If we
talk about NB Rio 2.0 plan, then
this coverage is the most unique here. Here you
get Booster Plus Benefit. Your sum
insured will keep increasing by 100% every year and
depending on your variant,
you can get Booster Plus Benefit up to 10 times your sum insured.  You
can collect this which
is a cumulate bonus 100% every year Maximum
up to 10 times of your sum insured The next
important feature comes friends Restoration
Benefit What is Restoration Benefit When your
basic sum insured is used
for treatment along with that your cumulate bonus no
claim bonus is also used, after that
comes the turn of Restoration i.e. Reset
Benefit You can also use this sum insured
for treatment How many times in which plan
you will be able to use it and
what are the conditions First of all, under Elevate Plan
you get Efinaconazole
[Music]
You will be able to use up to 100% of sum insured
unlimited times under Elevate Plan,
whereas under HDFC RIG
Optima Secure Plan you can take up to 100%
of sum insured once in a policy year
in the standard policy, that is, in the
standard SDFC R Optima Secure
Plan you can
use the restore benefit only once a year  If we
talk about Ratio 2.0 plan, then here
you get the benefit of Ratio and Plus Life
Time, which should be triggered once, after that
forever up to 100% of sum insured
unlimited times Ratio and Benefit Bit will be
available to you. Do
you get the option of co-payment in these plans, through which
you can reduce your premium?
If we talk about IIC Lord Elevate plan,
here the option of co-payment is given,
you can choose co-payment from 10 to 50 percent,
whereas there is no option
of co-payment in Optima Secure and Ratio 2.0 plan
and if we talk about Annual
Aggregate Deductible, that is, some fixed
amount which you will have to pay within the whole year,
after that the coverage of the insurance company will
start, which is called Annual Aggregate Deductible, then
that option is given in the Elevate plan,
although inside the policy document,
but the option
of deductible is not showing anywhere on the website of the insurance company,
so we can consider it in this
plan.  You'll understand that it's not available within the plan, but
within the ADAC or Optima Secure plan, you get the option of a deductible, and
within Ratio 2.0, you also get the
option of a deductible. Now, friends, we've understood these coverage and
benefits. Now
comes a very important part of the video: add-
ons. Now, one of these plans, the Elevate plan, is
focused solely on advances. There are
more than 30 advances in this plan, allowing
you to modify the plan completely.
And within the ADAC or Optima Secure
and Ratio 2.2 plans, there are some add-ons
that are very important for those plans. Let's take a look at the
add-ons.
Which add-ons are available in each plan, which will give
you a little more clarity on the
limits to which you can customize your plan. So,
first, let's understand the add-ons of Elevate.
First, the
two IFNA features within it are optional. The
first add-on is IFIT Care, which allows you to make
one claim in your lifetime, up to an unlimited amount.
Let us understand this. If you
take this add-on, Infinite Care, then during the
lifetime of the policy, you can stretch any one claim up to an
unlimited amount.
Suppose my sum insured is ₹1 lakh, then
my limit for that claim will not be ₹1 lakh;
every limit above that will be removed and it will be
covered up to an unlimited amount.
However, I will have to decide whether to take this add-on, Infinite Care,
within the first two years of taking the policy.
After that, I
cannot opt ​​for it. Once I take this add-on,
it will remain dead in my policy until I use this feature. The
second infit benefit that you get
under the Elevate plan is the
Power Booster, which can also be called Infit Cumulative Bonus.
If you take this add-on,
your cumulative bonus will increase by 100% of the
sum insured every year and this can be up to an
unlimited amount, such as
within the ratio of 2.2.  There is a capping of
maximum 10 times. So there
is no such capping here. If you have taken an add-
on for Power Booster in the ICICI Lombard Elevate plan, the
next add-on in the Elevate plan will provide
Jump Start. What Jump
Start means is that we
speed up our process through a jump, that is, we
reach a place speedily. So Jump Start is
related to the six
listed illnesses and medical conditions
that are visible on the screen right now.
If
you want to end the waiting period for any of these conditions, then
you will have to take the Jump Start add-on. You can get coverage for
any of these pre-exiting diseases from the 31st day.
If you have
taken the add-on Jump Start in the ICICI
Lombard Elevate plan, the next add-on
is Room Modify because the
room rent limit in the standard Elevate plan is for a
single private AC room. You can modify it.
You can also book any room.
That is,
you will have to pay extra for any category of room.  You
can also opt for twin-sharing rooms,
meaning you can accommodate two patients in one room.
Your premium will be slightly reduced. You
can also set a percentage-based room rent limit. You will receive room rent at 1% of your sum insured,
and
ICU treatment at 2% of your sum insured.
You can
also reduce or modify the waiting period. This includes the
maternity waiting period, specific
disease waiting period, or pre-
accident disease waiting period.
You can extend all these three waiting periods from 36 months
to 24 months or even 12 months.
Under the Elevate plan, you
also get maternity benefits, but
they must be availed as an add-on.
Maternity charges, delivery charges,
newborn baby coverage, and
vaccination coverage are optional. It also
comes with a "Be Fit" rider,
which is an add-on that allows
you to avail online and offline OPD
coverage.  That is, you can get doctor's
consultations online through the mobile app
and by visiting the physical panel hospitals where
doctors are located.
If you travel abroad a lot
or you feel that your
health insurance policy should also include foreign
coverage, then
you will have to take the add-on of Worldwide Coverage in the Elevate plan.
Through this, you can also get this coverage. If you
need personal accidental coverage, it will be available
as an add-on. If you need critical illness
coverage,
you can add it to your policy as an add-on under the Elevate plan.
Apart from this, there is an add-
on of Claim Protector, that is, consumable
items, since they are not part of the standard policy,
you can also increase the coverage of your plan by adding Claim Protector to your policy.
Apart from this, there is a Kavale Sense
benefit, Compassionate Visit, these can also be added as add-ons
to your Elevate plan.
And
you also get an add-on of Durable Equipment Coverage, that is,
durable
medical items that are used for the long term.  You can
also avail coverage of up to ₹1 lakh for equipment that is listed as durable equipment
in the IA Lombard Elevate plan. There is a fairly extensive list of
add-ons in the Elevate plan.
In comparison, let's compare the add-ons available in Optima Secure and Ratio 2.0. The
first add-on
you get in the Optima Secure plan is
hospital cash. That is, for the number
of days the patient is admitted in the hospital,
they will be given some daily benefit for a maximum of a certain number of days because during that
time, they are facing some loss of earnings or
some of their other expenses are also increasing.
You can avail the Unlimited Restoration add-on
because ADFC Rig Optima Secure only
provides restoration benefit once a year. So, as an add-on, you
can also add Unlimited Restoration to your Optima Secure plan. Annual
Aggregate Deductible: As I mentioned,
this is also available to you as an add-on.
However, the deductible amount
is also quite flexible which is ₹2500000 for
Permanent Total Disability and Perma
Coverage of nant partial disability can also be
done through add-ons in the Optima Secure plan.
If you want OPD coverage in the Optima Secure plan, then
you will also have to take the add-on called Well Being.
Through this, you
can also cover OPD consultations in your health insurance
plan. Now friends, let us understand the add-ons of Ratio 2.2. The
first important add-on is
Safeguard and Safeguard Plus.
If you take these add-ons, then your non-
medical items which are consumable items will
also be covered. Along with this, your sum insured will automatically increase with the same premium in proportion to the Consumer
Price Index, that is, the rising inflation rate
in the country. That is, as
inflation increases, the
sum insured of your policy will keep
increasing simultaneously so that it does not decrease. And the third
benefit is that if any claim comes, then it will
not have any impact on your Booster Plus benefit if you have taken the Safeguard add-on.  If you have
taken a Safeguard Plus add-on up to a claim of ₹5000000, then a claim of ₹1 lakh will
not affect your Booster Plus benefit,
but this is only if you choose this add-on.
You also get the hospital cash add-on in Ratio 2.0.
You will also get the option of annual aggregate deductible in Ratio 2.0
plan, in which you
can reduce your policy premium.
Your
premium can be significantly lower compared to the amount of annual aggregate deductible you choose. However,
you will have to pay the same amount yourself throughout the year, only
after that will the coverage of Ratio 2.2
start. Acute Care is an add-on
under Hari Asho 2.0, under which you
can avail OPD consultations.
By taking the Disease Management add-on, your BP
and diabetes will be covered from day one itself.
If you want these
chronic illnesses covered,  If you want coverage from day one,
you should take the disease management add-on.
Now, friends, you've understood the add-ons,
meaning the options available to
modify your policy.
You've also understood the optional coverages of all three plans. The one with the most
options is the
Elevate plan, which is the
latest plan. Whatever the company brings out as the
latest, there are bound to be some
improvements. Now, friends, let's
understand some of the highlights of these three policies that
make them so popular and special. Then, we'll
also explore some of the shortcomings that
we find in this plan. So, let's
understand the highlights of the Conclusion plan. The first special feature is the
theme of Infit. This plan offers an infinite
sum insured (IFNA) reset benefit (
IFNA) for policyholders, ensuring that
their coverage is not limited. This is both
unique and a good thing
for policyholders.  Additionally, the
maximum entry age for adults is
125 years, meaning you can still take this plan if you fall into a higher age group. There is
no age capping. The third special feature
of the Elevate plan is its flexibility. The
insurance company itself says that
you have never seen such a personalized plan before.
Because the
insurance company has offered the standard features in many plans as add-
ons. If a feature is missing
in a plan, it has
also been included as an add-on
in the Elevate plan so that there is
no complaint that the
policyholder is not getting the coverage they needed. Those who
want it can choose from add-ons. The
rest of the
basic coverages are included in the standard policy. The
last good thing about the Elevate plan is
that the waiting period can also be reduced.
Now, suppose I have a pre-
aging disease and I
want to reduce its waiting period. I will buy that policy today. 3
years or 4 years  If it covers after then there is no benefit of that.
I can prepay my coverage by paying extra money,
so this is also a
very flexible option. If we talk about the
special features of ATF Seer Optima Secure, then
here Secure Benefit means
two times coverage from day one and
if you have Super Secure plan then
you get three times coverage there, which
increases your coverage amount significantly and
gives a lot of strength to your sum insured.
Along with this, there is Plus Benefit, that is, the
sum insured will increase every year on 50% and will
go up to a maximum of 100%. This is also a very good
feature and Protect Benefit, that is,
consumer items are also
given standard coverage in this plan. However,
under the Elevate plan and the Ratio 2.0 plan,
you will have to take these as donations. Now let's talk about the
special features of the Ratio 2.0 plan.
First of all, there is
Booster Plus Benefit. Your sum insured can
increase up to 10 times. This is a very good
thing, that is, believe me.  If I have a policy of ₹ lakh,
I can extend the coverage up to ₹ crore.
If I have bought the right variant, then even in
smaller variants,
you can extend it up to five times.
This increases your coverage. You do
n't have to worry about your sum insured falling short
or running out of money for treatment.
If you have bought the right variant, then one of the most
unique features is Lock the Clock, which means that once you
buy the policy,
your premium will remain the same until you make a claim. Suppose I
bought the policy at the age of 30-32 years and did not make a claim
till the age of 50 years,
my premium will remain the same. There will be
no age-wise revision for the age of 32 years,
but whenever I make a claim, the premium will be charged as per my age
slab.
This is a one-of-a-kind and
most unique feature which you will not get in any other policy.
After this, the best
feature that comes is Reassure Plus, which means that
only on the first claim in the entire life, you  You
cannot use the Reassure Plus benefit.
After that, your
Reassure sum insured, which is
equal to your sum insured, will always be
available for use. In the other
two plans,
you cannot use it on the first claim every year. However,
if you have taken the Reassure 2.0 plan, then
you have to waive only the first claim in your entire lifetime.
After that, Reassure Plus will be
available for your use. Apart from this,
you can also take the Smart Health Rider in it, in
which you can avail OPD benefits and will
also be able to avail OPD coverage. Now
friends, there are some shortcomings of these plans. Let us understand them once. First of all,
if you look at the Elevate plan, any educated policy holder
who is aware
can modify this plan well and personalize it well
according to his needs. But if there is a new policy holder
who does not know much because there is a
lot of lack of awareness, there are
very limited people associated with health insurance, either those
who have ever dealt with claims or those who are
aware.  If you do a lot of research about your financial decisions, then there are
30 add-ons in the Elevate plan.
If you don't know their coverages and how to
use these add-ons, then
you can get quite confused. Secondly, the
chances of mis-selling can also increase. It is possible that the
insurance company or any advisor may
give you unnecessary advice to increase the premium. So, there is a little bit of coverage in the
standard policy.
All the coverage is included in it, so
your decision-making work gets reduced.
However, this is also its plus point. The plan has been
made flexible through more add-ons,
but it depends on how one uses it. I do
n't see any shortcomings in HDFC ARG Optima Secure. The
only thing I need is clarification on modern treatments.
If they
clarify in their policy document
how much coverage will be available, up to what limit,
whether there is any limit or not, and which
modern treatments will be covered, then this can be
a very good thing for this plan
and ratio  If we talk about the 2.0 plan, there
is a drawback related to modern treatment here too, that is, the
capping of ₹1 lakh on robotic surgeries should
not have been there when all modern
treatments are covered, then
if there was no capping of ₹1 lakh on these robotic surgeries, then
this plan also has
no competition. Now friends, after comparing
everything like coverage, benefits, add-ons, eligibility, it is the
turn to compare the most important thing and that is the
price of the policy because the
claim coverage will be useful when you use it,
but we have to pay the premium every year, every
quarter, every half yearly. So let us
also check which policy will cost you how much money.
For price comparison, the standard family size
I have taken is of two adults and two
children. The age of the adults is 38 and 35
years and the age of the children is 12 years and 9 years.
Here I have taken the sum insured of ₹1
lakh because here the sum insured  There are many things like sum insured's
cumet bonus or restoration benefit
which can increase your sum insured,
so I have taken the basic sum
insured of only ₹1 lakh and the
address of the policy holder, I have
taken it here for daily, that is, if your policy has
zone based pricing, then it will
come in zone one only, so let us understand the premium of this family size
once, if we talk about
IIC Lombard Elevate plan, then
I have added two dons in the standard policy, that is,
I am telling you the premium by adding two optional covers, the
first optional cover is room
rent, that is, the room
rent is of standard
single private AC room, but I have
modified it and made it any room pay
because there is
no capping of room rent in the other two plans also, the second add-on
which I have added is power booster
which will give you unlimited inflated NCB i.e.
cumet bonus, so after adding these two dons, you get a
sum insured of ₹1 lakh and the
family size which I have mentioned.  For this coverage,
this policy holder will have to pay ₹1,265 for 1 year
to this family. This price is
inclusive of GST. And if we talk about the same
family size, same coverage of ₹1 lakh and
Delhi address,
if we take HDFC and Optima Secure plan, then how much will it cost us?
In this, you will have to pay ₹6298 for one year to the
insurance company. The
coverages that we have understood here, which are
mentioned in this plan, you will get them for this much money.
Now comes the turn of Ratio 2.0
plan, so here for the same coverage of the same family size,
you will have to
pay ₹3510 8 annually at the Delhi address, that is,
you will have to pay this much money in a year. Now
these prices that we have understood here are one-time
prices and you can also take different ads
in your policy, but
after taking this almost similar coverage,
you will have to pay this much premium in all these three plans.
Now comes the turn of premium revision, that
is, what is the frequency, how
often are the premiums revised?  There can be two or three
ways in which revisions can occur. The first is
inflation-based, that is, due to inflation. The
second is that some new
features may have been added to the policy. The third
is age-related. When your age band changes
every 5 or 10 years,
your premium also changes, which is the
most frequent among these three plans. The website that provides the most frequency
is
hdfcfund.com. I hope to
bring to your mind a clear picture of the coverage benefits and add-ons related to all three plans, along with their pros and cons, so that whatever your
decision is, whether to buy these plans,
port them, or any other decision,
you can take it with confidence. If
you have any questions related to any coverage or feature related to these plans,
please ask in the comments section.
You can also tell us how you liked the video in the comments section. To
show your love and support, you can also like and share the video. For
our viewers who are new
or have been following us for a long time,
But till now they have not subscribed to the channel,
so please subscribe to the channel
if you feel that the videos coming on this channel
create some value for you, then by
subscribing and pressing the notification bell icon,
you will keep
getting notifications of important videos timely and most importantly,
you will keep getting very important videos on Insurance Impact's channel in a
timely manner.
I, Harvinder Singh, now
take your permission, I will take your permission in the next video, till then take care of yourself,
stay happy and stay healthy, Jai Hind